What's going on guys.
Welcome to your first project.
So I wanted to do something pretty simple but something that's pretty common for the first project of
the course.
And we're gonna do a form validator.
So we're gonna do some client side form validation and we'll first create the form with each team out
then we're gonna style it with CSX and then we're gonna go ahead and add our javascript now to begin
with.
We're gonna do this kind of I guess the easy way but not the best code.
Just a bunch of if statements with some validation and then we're going to completely refactor it and
create specific functions for each type of validation for instance to check required or check the length
or check to see if the passwords match.
So we'll write it in one way and then we'll completely refactor it to make it cleaner and make it more
scalable if we want to add more fields it'll be easy to add the validation.
OK so just to give you an example here.
If I were to submit I get a bunch of errors.
So every field is required.
Some of them have a men and max length so user name must be at least three characters.
If I type in Brad and submit you'll see that that's now highlighted green which means that it passed
for the email.
So if I just type in anything that's not going to work I to test at test dot com that's going to pass.
Now for the password has to be at least six characters if I do let's do three characters and submit
you'll see it still get that error.
Also the passwords don't match and they have to.
So it's two three four five six one two three four five six submit and now they both pass.
OK so we'll be dealing with JavaScript along with CSX because obviously we need to add certain classes
to make this green or red or display or hide the error messages.
So we're gonna go ahead and get started.